Where Hands Touch is a war, drama, romance film directed by Amma Asante.
Germany, 1944.
Leyna, the 15-year old daughter of a white German mother and a black African father, meets Lutz, a compassionate member of the Hitler
Youth whose father is a prominent Nazi soldier, and they form an unlikely connection in this quickly changing world.
Leyna, played by Amandla Stenberg.
Lutz, played by George MacKay.
Kerstin, played by Abbie Cornish.
Heinz, played by Christopher Eccleston.
Koen, played by Tom Sweet.
Juttner, played by Alec Newman.
Where Hands Touch is a 2018 romantic war drama film written and directed by Amma Asante and starring
Amandla Stenberg, George MacKay, Abbie Cornish, Christopher Eccleston, and Tom Sweet.
It tells a fictional story of Leyna (Stenberg), a teenage girl under threat
because of her mixed heritage while surviving in Nazi Germany.
The film is based on historical record of the
persecution of black people in Nazi Germany.
The film is a British, Belgian, Canadian, and Irish co-production.
Principal photography on the film began in November 2016 in Belgium
and lasted for a month, wrapping up in December 2016.
Where Hands Touch premiered at the Toronto
International Film Festival on 9 September 2018.
It was released theatrically in the United States on 14
September 2018 by Vertical Entertainment.
It received mixed reviews, with praise directed at Stenberg's
performance, and criticism toward its screenplay.
The film explores themes of nazi, jew persecution, hitler
youth, coming of age, interracial romance.
The tone is emotional.